(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T13:18:51.580888",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
さてと、
So anyway...
今日は風真の一周年の配信だ！
Today is Kazama's 1st anniversary stream!
そろそろ本番だし、パソコンの準備しよっと。
It's almost time for the main event, so let's get the PC ready.
ちょうど1年前はデビューの前にパソコン壊しちゃったでござるからな。
You see, exactly one year ago, right before my debut, I broke my PC, you know?
さすがに1年も経つわけだし、同じことが二度起こるはずが……
It's been a whole year, so surely it won't happen twice...
あ……
Ah.
あ？
Huh?
あ、あれ？
Huh? Huh?
動かないでござるな。
It's not working...
こういうときは、叩けば直るっと！
When this happens, if I hit it, it'll fix itself—
ってだめ！
Nope.
ねえ、ちょっと……
Hey, wait...
おい！おいおい！
Hey! Hey!
あー？
Huh?
なんで煙出てるでござるな？おい！
Why is it smoking?
うわ！ 煙々が出てる！
Whoa! Smoke is coming out!
うわ、大変！大変！どうしよう！やばい！煙が！うわー！
Oh no! Oh no! What should I do? Oh no, smoke is—!
暫し待たれよー
Hold on a moment—
壊してしまいましたね。
Well, I broke it again, didn't I?
また壊してしまったでござる。
I've gone and broken it again...
パルス、そのPCを
My PC...
まさかね、また壊れてしまうとか思っても見なかったでござる。
Never thought it would break again...
“なぜ壊れてしまったのですか？”
"Why did it break?"
正直、叩けば直ると思っていたでござるよ。まあ叩いて直るどころか、今度は爆発してしまったんでござるが。
To think hitting it would fix it...
“1周年配信を迎えている未来の自分に一言ありますか？”
"Do you have any words for your future self holding the 1st-anniversary stream?"
いやまた逃げられないでござるよ風真。こうなったら腹くくって皆の前に出て精神誠意、謝罪とその心を皆の前に見せるでござる。
Kazama, if this happens again, steel your resolve, step in front of everyone, and show them your heart and sincerity!
あーあ、えー皆様
Good evening, everyone.
この度は一周年配信の前にパソコンどもを直るかなって叩いた挙句、壊してしまい皆様並びにご心配、そして運営様にご迷惑をおかけしまして本当に申し訳ございませんでした。
I am truly sorry.
しかし、一年前の風真とは違う！
However!
この1年で風真は成長しました！自分のパソコンぐらいアイドルパワーで直してやるでござる！
This year, Kazama has grown!
歌って踊って成長した姿を見せるでござるよ！
I'll show you how much I've grown by singing and dancing!
いざ、ライブ会場へ！レッツゴー！うおおお！行くぞ！行くぞ！行くぞー！
Now, let's go to the live venue! Let's go!
きたぞきたぞきたぞー！ただいま！皆様、こんばんはでござる！
Good evening, everyone!
ホロライブ6期生ホロックスの幼女謀、サムライの風真いろはでござるー！やっほー！お待たせしました！
HoloLive 6th Generation HoloX's wildcard, Kazama Iroha!
今日は風真いろはの1周年記念ライブにお越しいただきありがとうございます！そして直前でパソコンのみならず、あの枠も破壊してしまいまして本当に申し訳ございませんでした。
Today, thank you so much for coming to the Kazama Iroha 1st Anniversary Live!
もうどんだけもの壊すねんってめっちゃ皆様思ってるかもしれないんですけど、色々ありましたが無事に1周年配信をスタートすることができました！ありがとうございます！
You must all think I break a lot of things, but we've successfully started the 1st-anniversary live stream! Thank you!
あ、今日はハッシュタグ、えっとこっち、えっと風真いろは1周年ライブでたくさんつぶやいて、スクショとかもいっぱいバズーマしてくれると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
Today, with the hashtag #KazamaIroha1stAnniversaryLive, please tweet a lot and flood SNS with screenshots. I'd be super happy! Let's go!
はい、ね、今日はここでたくさん歌って踊ってアイドルパワーを貯めるでござる。
Today, we're going to sing and dance a lot to build up our idol power!
あ、そう、アイドルパワーが何かってね、そう説明しないでおくでござるな。それでは、説明しよう。
Let me explain what idol power is.
こちらです！
It's this!
まだゼロのままでござるか。あ、そう、このパワーは風真がアイドルっぽいことをすればメーターが貯まって、
It's still at zero.
そんでこのパワーがマックスになったら、この1周年のために頑張って準備したアートとかそれとかこれとかいっぱいこのデータが詰まったあのパソコンを
and once this power reaches max, we can revive the PC that got jammed with all the data for the 1st anniversary!
復活させることができるという考えでござる！きっと直る！
That's my idea, it has to work!
てかパソコンが直らないと、せっかく皆様のために準備したあれが、そうあれが発表できないでござる！やばい、どうしよう！
If the PC doesn't work, all my prep for everyone... wait, I can't even announce it! Oh no, what should I do?
まあでもね、やるしかない！ということで、さっそくアイドルパワーを貯めていくぞ！行くぞ！行くぞ！
Well, I have no choice! Let's build up that idol power! Let's go!
それでは皆様聴いてください。1曲目、風真の中でアイドルといえばこれ！いきます！ハートはお手上げ
Listen up, everyone. Song number one: When it comes to idols, this is it! Here we go!
ハートはお手上げ
Heart wa Oteage
yes ！ 君 の シルエット
Yes! Your silhouette,
きらきらり きらめい て
sparkling like a sea of stars.
走り出し た 気持ち は 今 境界線 を 飛び越える の
My feelings are soaring over the boundary line!
ハート つかまえ て
Capture my heart!
降り出し た 雨 の 中 歩幅 を 合わせ て 歩い た
When the rain started to fall, we walked in sync,
傘 を たたく 雨粒 の ビート 私 の 鼓動 の よう
to the beat of the raindrops on our umbrellas, like my heartbeat.
信号 赤 の まま 時間 止まっ て
Signals stay red, I wish time would stop,
苦しい くらい 思い が あふれ て く
overflowing with emotions that hurt.
yes ！ 君 の シルエット
Yes! Your silhouette,
時間よ 止まって
Stop, time...
苦しいくらい想いがあふれてく
Feelings so painful they overflow.
恋人のシルエット
A lover's silhouette
ゆらゆらに揺らめいて
swaying and flickering.
動き出した世界もまた瞳はスローモーション
The world starts moving again, my eyes in slow motion.
言葉にできない不器用な君のこと
Your awkwardness that I can't put into words—
全部ぎゅっと抱きしめてよ 境界線を飛び越えるよ
I want to hold it all tight and cross the boundary line!
もっと笑わないで ハートはお手上げ
Don't smile so much, I totally surrender to your heart!
真夜中にスマホが鳴り 君の名前が光って 嬉しいのに切なくなる
My phone rings in the middle of the night, your name lights up, and though I'm happy, it makes me sad.
切なくなる 終わらない迷路みたい 優しくしないで
It's like an endless maze, please don't be so gentle—
もてなくなルから 寄せては返す想いが
or I won't be able to handle it. Feelings rush in and recede...
ざわめいて
...surging up.
恋のワンフレーズ どこまでも鳴り響いて
A phrase of love echoes on endlessly,
色づいてく 気持ちはいま 誰にも求められない
coloring my feelings now, which no one can ask for.
素直になれない 甘野じゃくな私は 全部ぎゅっと抱きしめてね
I can't be honest, I'm a little shy and stubborn, so hold all of me tight!
明日の未来へ飛び込むから 覚悟しててね ハートを捕まえて
I'm diving into tomorrow's future, so be prepared and catch my heart!
真夜中にスマホが鳴り 君の名前が光って
My phone rings in the middle of the night, your name lights up,
嬉しいのに切なくなる
and though I'm happy, it makes me sad.
愛の夢を描く 天国への Yes, No 壁だ ああ 浮いたの
Drawing dreams of love, stepping up to heaven—Yes, No, a wall, ah, floating...
君を傍だといいのにね 恋してる 君のシルエット
I wish you were right by me. I'm in love with your silhouette,
ゆらゆらに揺らめいて 動き出した世界もまた
swaying and flickering. The world that started moving again,
瞳はスローモーション 言葉にできない
my eyes in slow motion, unable to put into words—
不器用な君のこと 全部ぎゅっと抱きしめたら 境界線を飛び越えるよ
Your awkwardness, if I hold it all tight, I'll cross the boundary line!
もっと笑わないで ハートはお手上げ
Don't smile so much, I totally surrender!
Don't smile so much, I totally surrender to your heart!
はい！というわけで1曲目は風真の大好きなお友達、アイリスさんの「ハートはお手上げ」でしたー！どうだったかな？
Hi! So the first song was my dear friend Irys's "Heart wa Oteage"! How was it?
コメント見えてるぞ。この可愛さにはおて上げ…それは本当でござるか？
I can see the chat. "This cuteness is too much to handle"—is that true?
やった！頑張った甲斐があった！あっめっちゃ可愛いって言ってくれてる！みんなありがとう、頑張ったよ！
Yay! All my hard work paid off! Ah, you're saying I'm super cute! Thank you everyone, I worked hard!
もう本当にね、風真のなかでアイドルの手本にしている方なので、1周年でね大好きなその方の「ハートはお手上げ」をやらせていただきました！ありがとう！アイドルっぽかった？
Truly, she's my idol role model, so for my 1st anniversary I got to perform her song "Heart wa Oteage"! Thank you! Did it feel idol-like?
あ、アイドルっぽかった？ぽかったかな？お、ということはこれでアイドルパワーは…上がってる！やったー！上がってるよみんな、やったー！ありがとう！
Ah, did it feel idol-like? Did it? Oh, that means my idol power has... gone up! Yay! It went up, everyone, yay! Thank you!
この調子でね、ガンガン頑張っていきますので！そしてそしてね、ゲストの方も駆けつけてくれているので、お楽しみ！
I'll keep doing my best at this pace! And also, guests have rushed over to join us, so look forward to it!
あ、昨日、昨日追加したパワー中身もいっぱい使ってくれてありがとう！よし、それでは次の1曲、曲いきますよー！レッツゴー！
Ah, thank you for using all the power-ups I added yesterday! Alright, now for the next song—let's go!
会いたくて 恋しくて 離れて あの日はもうこない
Wanting to see you, yearning for you, separated—those days will never return.
等身大の自分 遠くの君に手を振ろう Catch your hand, say Yeah, Oh!
My true self, waving to you far away—catch your hand, say Yeah, Oh!
淡い香りが漂う 季節が巡りくる
The season of faint fragrance comes around again.
会いたくて 恋しくて 離れて
To meet, to love, and to part,
あの日はもうない
that day will never come again.
等身大の自分 遠くの君に手を振ろう 掲げろ
I'll wave goodbye to you from afar! Raise them up!
Put your hands up! Yeah! Oh!
淡い香りが漂う季節が巡りくる
The season of faint fragrance returns,
心弾ませていた頃が今蘇るよ
reviving the days when my heart soared.
初めて恋をしたんだ 何もかもが輝いていた
It was my first love, and everything shone brightly.
少しの時間でさえも 一緒に時間を刻んでいた
Even for just a little while, we shared our time together.
桜咲いた木の下で君の声を
Your voice under the blooming cherry trees
春風が邪魔して聞こえない
was drowned out by the spring breeze.
さよならじゃないと願った
I wished it wouldn't be a goodbye.
会いたくて 恋しくて 離れて
To meet, to love, and to part—
あの日の笑顔が舞い散って
those smiles of that day scatter away.
いつまでもと誓った 君はもういない
Though we vowed forever, you are no longer here.
叶うなら桜が舞い降りる 来年の今も
If wishes come true, may cherry blossoms fall next year too,
肩並べ写真でも撮りたいな あの日はもうこない
taking a photo side by side—that day won't return.
会いたい 見えない 手の平に
I want to see you, but my outstretched palm holds nothing.
ほら?花びら 空に光る星が
Look, petals and stars shining in the sky
傷口をつくんだ
only sting my wounds.
もう恋なんてしないよと 君に一番言いたかった
"I'll never fall in love again," I wanted to tell you most.
雨が降って 二人で入った傘も
The umbrella we shared in the rain,
待ち合わせしたあの駅も
and the station where we used to meet—
もう一人じゃ行きたくないよ
I don't want to walk alone anymore.
「好きだった」過去形な手紙は今更いらない
Letters in the past tense like "I loved you" are useless now.
別れ際優しくするなら 側にいてほしい
If we must part, I want you to be gentle and stay by my side.
来るはずのない場所であの日を待っている
Waiting for that day in a place we shouldn't meet,
一人ぼっちの僕を 思い出のあの曲を小さい声で歌う
all alone, I sing that memorable song in a soft voice.
もう恋なんてしないよなんて ただの嘘で
Saying "I'll never love again" was just a lie.
もう忘れられないなんて ただの冗談で
Saying "I can't forget you" was just a joke.
忘れたくなくて結局君に恋していたいよ
I didn't want to forget; in the end, I'm still in love with you.
会いたくて 恋しくて 離れて
To meet, to love, and to part—
あの日の笑顔が舞い散って
those smiles of that day scatter away.
いつまでもと誓った 君はもういない
Though we vowed forever, you are no longer here.
ラジオからあの曲 二人でいた部屋で
As that song plays on the radio in the room we shared,
自然と涙が溢れ出る
tears overflow naturally.
別れ際の笑顔が一番愛しく見えた
Your smile at parting looked the most precious.
咲かせよう 桜が舞い降りて 弱い自分から抜け出せる
Let cherry blossoms fall so I can escape my weak self,
涙の音奏でる旋律を歌う
singing the melody woven by the sound of tears.
ラジオから春の歌 もうそんな季節ね
A spring song plays on the radio—such a season already.
さよならをぐっと飲み込んだ
I swallowed hard on our goodbye.
思い出の1ページ 色鮮やかに残る
A page of memories remains vividly colored.
会いたくて 恋しくて 離れて
To meet, to love, and to part,
あの日の笑顔が舞い散って
the smiles of that day are scattering.
いつまでもと誓った 君はもういない
Though we vowed forever, you are no longer here.
叶うなら 桜が舞い降りる 来年の今も
If possible, let cherry blossoms fall next year too.
肩並べ写真でも撮りたいな あの日はもうこない
I want to take a photo together—that day won't come again.
ラジオからあの曲 二人でいた部屋で 自然と涙が溢れ出る
Tears fall naturally in the room we shared.
別れ際はもう笑顔が一番そっと見えた
Your parting smile is the dearest thing I can see.
咲かせよう 桜が舞い降りて 弱い自分から抜け出せる
Let the cherry blossoms fall so I can break free from my weak self,
涙の音奏でる旋律を歌う
singing the melody woven by the sound of tears.
ラジオから春の歌 もうそんな季節で
A spring song plays on the radio, reminding me of that season.
さようならをずっと飲み込んだ
Saying goodbye, I swallowed the words deep inside.
思い出の1ページ 色鮮やかに残る
The page of memories remains brilliant and bright.
あずあず、一緒に歌ってくれてありがとうございますでござる。
Thank you all so much for tuning in so quickly!
こちらこそ誘ってくれてありがとう！よろはちゃんでございます！
Thank you so much for joining in too! Yororoha!
イェーイ！
Yay!
この「桜ロック」はあずあずの声にぴったりだなと思って選曲しました！
We thought this song fit AZKi's voice so well, so we chose it!
そうなんです。今回はね、いろはちゃんに選曲してもらって初めてこの曲歌いました！
That's right! And this is the first time I've sung this song with Iroha-chan!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
二人でハモったり、そしてユニゾンしたり、ラップもしちゃったりして
We harmonized together, sang in unison, and even rapped a bit—
可愛い振り付けだったりして、楽しかったですね！
it was such a cute choreography too, wasn't it? So fun!
ほんとに！いろはちゃん本当の1周年おめでとう！
Really! Iroha-chan, huge congratulations on your 1st anniversary!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
あずあとはAndroidがあるの立ってみたと、長らくコラボぶりでござるな。
And earlier, we actually performed with the Android models—it was our long-awaited collaboration!
また一緒に歌えて嬉しいし！
I'm so happy we got to sing together again!
今日はステージの上だ！やったー！
And today, we got to do it on stage! Yay!
このステージきたかった！やったー！
We finally got to perform this on stage! Yay!
アイドルっぽさ全開なのでござるな。
It feels so idol-like and full of energy!
お、どういうことは？
What does that mean?
これでまたアイドルパワーが止まったはずでござるな。
Does this mean our idol power is stopping?
おっ？
Oh?
そうだな。こっち。そ。
That's right. Over here. Yeah.
おっ？
Oh?
あー！
Ah!
お、たまってる！
Oh, it's building up!
やったー！
Yay!
よかった、よかった！
Good, good!
やったね、やった！
We did it, yay!
また絶対にふたりで一緒に歌おうね！ そっちなのでござる！
Let's definitely sing together again! That's how it is!
それでは1人目のゲストは あずあずでしたー！
Now, our first guest was AZKI!
好きでしたー！ありがとう！
Loved it! Thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ガラス玉ひとつ 落とされた
A glass marble was dropped,
追いかけてもうひとつ落っこちた
and when I chased it, another fell.
ひとつ分の陽だまりに ひとつだけ残ってる
In a single spot of sunlight, only one remains.
心臓が始まった時 嫌でも人は場所を取る
When the heartbeat began, people take up space whether they like it or not.
奪われないように守り続けてる
Continuing to protect it so it won't be stolen.
汚さずに保ってきた手でも 汚れて見えた
Even hands kept clean looked stained.
記憶を疑う前に 記憶に疑われてる
Before doubting my memories, my memories doubt me.
必ず僕らは出会うだろう 同じ鼓動の音を目印にして
Surely we will meet, using the same heartbeat as our guide.
ここに居るよ いつだって呼んでるから
I'm right here, always calling out for you,
くたびれた理由が重なって揺れる時
when worn-out reasons pile up and tremble,
生まれた意味を知る
we learn the meaning of birth.
存在する限り 仕方ないから場所を取る
As long as we exist, we take space because we must.
ひとつ分の陽だまりに ふたつはちょっと入れない
Two can't quite fit into a single spot of sunlight.
ガラス玉ひとつ落とされた 落ちた時何が弾き出した
A glass marble was dropped; what bounced out when it fell?
奪い取った場所で 光を浴びた
Basking in the light at the place I seized.
数えた足跡など 気付けば数字でしかない
The footprints I counted are just numbers before I knew it.
知らなきゃいけないことは どうやら1と0の間
What we need to know seems to lie between 1 and 0.
初めて僕らは出会うだろう 同じ悲鳴の旗を目印にして
For the first time we will meet, using the same banner of screams as our guide.
忘れないで いつだって呼んでるから
Don't forget, I'm always calling out for you,
重ねた理由をふたりで埋める時
when we fill the piled-up reasons together,
約束が交わされる
a promise is exchanged.
鏡なんだ僕らは互いに それぞれのカルマを映すため
We are mirrors to each other, reflecting our respective karma,
汚れた手と手で触り合って 形が分かる
touching hands with stained palms so we know our shape.
ここに居るよ 確実に触れるよ ひとりの陽だまりに僕らはいる
I'm right here, we can truly touch, existing in a solitary patch of sunlight.
忘れないで いつだって呼んでるから 同じガラス玉の内側の方から
Don't forget, I'm always calling out from the inside of the same glass marble.
そうさ必ず僕らは出会うだろう 同じ悲鳴の旗を目印にして
Yes, surely we will meet, using the same banner of screams as our guide.
忘れないで いつだって呼んでるから
Don't forget, I'm always calling out for you,
沈めた理由に十字架を立てるとき
when we raise a cross over the buried reasons,
約束が果される
the promise is fulfilled.
僕らはひとつになる
We become one.
ここに居るよ 確かに触れるよ ひとりの陽だまりに僕らはいる
I'm right here, we can truly touch, we are in a solitary patch of sunlight.
忘れないで いつだって呼んでるから 同じガラス玉の内側の方から
Don't forget, I'm always calling out from the inside of the same glass marble.
そうさ必ず僕らは出会うだろう 同じ悲鳴の旗を目印にして
Yes, surely we will meet, using the same banner of screams as our guide.
沈めた理由に十字架を立てるとき
When we raise a cross over the buried reasons,
約束は果される
the promise is fulfilled.
僕らはひとつになる
We become one.
あの日はたしか渚を今も思い出すんだ 砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
That day, I still remember the shore we looked upon, words carved in the sand, your silhouette behind.
寄り添う波が足元をよぎり 何かをすくう 君の遠い姿
Waves gently brushing against our feet, scooping something up, your distant figure.
夕映えの中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎて行く
In the evening glow, only the twilight passes by.
あの日見渡した渚を
The shore we looked out at that day
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched fireworks bloom in a flash of light.
きっと まだ 終わらない 夏が
Surely this summer is far from over,
曖昧な心を溶かして 繋いだ
melting our uncertain hearts together.
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
「あと何回君と同じ 花火を見られるかな」って
"I wonder how many times I'll see the same fireworks as you,"
笑う顔に何ができるんだろうか
what can I do for your smiling face?
傷つくこと 喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と衝動
Hurt and joy, recurring waves and impulses,
焦燥 最終列車の音
impatience, and the sound of the last train.
何度でも言葉にして 君を呼ぶよ
Again and again, I'll put it into words and call to you.
波間を選び もう一度
Choosing the space between waves, once more,
もう二度と悲しまずに 済むように
so that we never have to feel sad again.
はっと息を呑めば 消えちゃいそうな光が
A light that seemed it might vanish if we gasped,
きっと まだ胸に住んでいた
surely still lived within our hearts.
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は
A warm future we could touch if we reached out,
ひそかに二人を見ていた
was secretly watching the two of us.
パッと花火が 夜に咲いた 夜に咲いて
Fireworks bloomed in the night, bloomed in the night,
しっかり消えた 離さないで 離さないで
and cleanly faded away. Don't let go, don't let go.
もう少しだけ もう少しだけ このままで
Just a little longer, just a little longer, like this.
あの日見渡した渚を
The shore we looked out at that day
今も思い出すんだ
I still remember it now.
砂の上に取り残した言葉
The words left behind on the sand,
君の白い姿
the sight of your white figure.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched fireworks bloom in a flash of light.
きっと まだ 終わらない 夏が
Surely this summer is far from over,
曖昧な心を溶かして 繋いだ
melting our uncertain hearts together.
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
ラララ…
La la la...
というわけで、二人目のゲストはかなた先輩でございます！
And so, our second guest is Kanata-senpai!
一緒に歌ってくれてありがとうございます～！
Thank you so much for singing with me~!
呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thanks for inviting me!
一緒に水着姿歌とか歌いたいって、いつか一緒に歌いたいなって思ってました！
I've always wanted to sing together in swimsuit outfits like this someday!
うれしい！
I'm so happy!
ね、願いが叶って嬉しいでございます！
My wish came true, I'm so happy!
ありがとう〜
Thank you~
ね！いや私もね、一緒に歌いたいと思っていましたし、今回選んでくれた打ち上げ花火は…
Right? I've also wanted to sing together, and the song you chose, "Uchiage Hanabi", is...
あの、男の人と女の人とのデュエットの曲なので、これちょっとね、僕たちカップルみたいじゃない？
Um, since it's a duet between a guy and a girl, it's like we're a couple, right?
カップル！
A couple!
恥ずかしいけど嬉しいでございます！また一緒に お出かけしたいでございますね！
It's embarrassing, but I'm so happy! I'd love to go out on a date together again!
デートしようね！しようね！
Let's go on a date! Let's do it!
そしてそして見てください！お揃いの浴衣でございます！
And look at this! We have matching yukatas!
かわいいでしょう？お揃いにしていただいたので、お揃いにしていただきました！
Aren't they cute? We got them to match!
すてきに着けてもらいました。
We got dressed up so nicely.
ねえ！
Right!
そうだ。
That's right.
浴衣効果でママにアイドルパワーがたまったのではないでござるか？
Could the yukata effect have filled Mama's idol power?
アイドルパワーと…
Idol power and...
なんか出てきたな。
Something came out.
なんか、なんだろう、これ？おっ？
What is this? Oh?
たまった、たまった！
It's filling up, filling up!
よくわかんないけどやったー！
I don't really get it, but yay!
すごい！たまった！たまった！
Amazing! It filled up! Filled up!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Thank you!
また一緒に歌いましょうね。
Let's sing together again sometime.
歌おうね！絶対歌おう！
Let's sing! Let's definitely sing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
じゃあ…
Well then...
お供にこんど…
Next time, accompanying...
えー！ぜひいきましょう！またねー！
Yay! Let's definitely go! See you later!
小さきもの 作詞：三浦徳子 作曲：山移高寛
[Song: Chisakimono / Lyrics: Tokuko Miura / Music: Takahiro Yamaishi]
静かにただ見つめていた 小さきもの眠る顔
I was just quietly watching the sleeping face of the small one.
眉間にしわ 少しだけ寄せている
There are wrinkles slightly gathered between the eyebrows.
怖い夢なら 目を覚まして
If it's a scary dream, wake up.
水がこわくて しり込みしてた
I was hesitating, being afraid of the water.
あの残像が 呼び戻そうと 背中 押されては
Those afterimages trying to recall me, being pushed from behind...
やっと泳げた まるで 傷跡みたいです
I was finally able to swim, it's almost like a scar.
声が聞こえる ゆくべき道 指している
I can hear voices pointing to the path I must take.
さらさら流れる 風の中でひとり わたし うたっています
In the wind flowing smoothly, I am singing alone.
小さきもの それは私 私です まぎれもなく
The small one, that is me, it is me, unmistakably.
鏡の中 心細さだけが
In the mirror, only helplessness...
誰にも負けない 明日になるよ そしてわたしは
Tomorrow I won't lose to anyone, and I...
幼い頃に 少しずつ戻ってゆく
slowly return to my childhood days.
意味も知らず歌う 恋の歌を 褒めてくれた あの君に
Singing love songs without knowing the meaning, to you who praised me back then.
走ったりなるよ そしてわたしは
I'll run... and I...
幼い頃に 少しずつ もっとってい行く 意味も
slowly, increasingly returning to my childhood days, not even knowing the meaning...
知らず歌う 恋の歌を 褒めてくれた あの君に
Singing love songs, to you who praised me back then.
空を仰げば 満ちてくる 私の声が
When I look up at the sky, my voice fills up.
さらさら流れる 風の中で君も ふわり 舞い上がれ
In the wind flowing smoothly, you too, flutter and soar up.
声が聞こえる ゆくべき道 指している
I can hear voices pointing to the path I must take.
さらさら流れる 風の中でひとり わたし うたっています
In the wind flowing smoothly, I am singing alone.
声が聞こえる ゆくべき道 指している
I can hear voices pointing to the path I must take.
さらさら流れる 風の中でひとり わたし うたっています
In the wind flowing smoothly, I am singing alone.
大切なものは すぐそばにある そのことに 気づいた
The precious things are right beside us, I realized that.
空を仰げば 満ちてくる 私の声が
When I look up at the sky, my voice fills up.
さらさら流れる 風の中で君も ふわり 舞い上がれ
In the wind flowing smoothly, you too, flutter and soar up.
大切なものは すぐそばにある そのことに
The precious things are right beside us, in that...
気づいた
I realized.
静かに ただ 見つめてた
I gazed just in silence,
小さきもの 眠る顔
at the sleeping face of the little thing.
眉間にしわ少しだけ寄せてる
It had creases in the middle of its forehead.
怖い夢なら目を覚まして
If it's a scary dream, wake up.
水がこわくて しり込みしてた
I was afraid of the water and hesitated.
あの夏が よみがえるよ
That summer comes back to life.
背中押されて やっと泳げた
Pushed in the back, I finally swam.
まるで昨日みたいです
It feels just like yesterday.
声が聞こえる
I can hear a voice
ゆくべき道 指している
pointing to the path I should take.
さらさら流る 風の中で ひとり
Alone in the gently flowing wind,
わたし うたっています
I am singing.
小さきもの それは私
The little thing, that is me,
私です まぎれなく
without a doubt, it is me.
鏡の中 心細さだけが
Inside the mirror, only vulnerability
誰にも負けない 明日になるよ
will become a tomorrow that won't lose to anyone.
空を仰げば
When I look up at the sky,
満ちてくる わたしの声が
my overflowing voice
さらさら流る 風の中で 君も
in the gently flowing wind, you too
ふわり 舞い上がれ
soar up gently.
はい！というわけで、
So,
小さきものを歌わせていただきました！
I just sang "Chiisakimono"!
どうだったでござるか？
How was it?
今ポケモンね、めっちゃま、この間も風也もやっているので、
Right now Pokémon is being played by everyone lately,
風真の大好きなポケモンジラーチの映画のね、主題歌を歌わせていただきました！
so I sang the movie theme song of Jirachi, Kazama's favorite Pokémon!
めっちゃ拍手ありがとう！
Thank you so much for the applause!
めっちゃみんなのそのパワーチャージしてくれてるの、見ててね、ありがとう！
Seeing you all charging up that power for me, thank you so much!
そして、今回なんと初公開、こちらのステージで秋になりました！
And this time, for the very first time, it became autumn on this stage!
見て、めっちゃきれい！すごい！すごくない？めっちゃきれい！すごい！
Look, it's so pretty! Amazing! Isn't it amazing? It's so pretty! Amazing!
今ね、初めからスタートして春、夏、秋までやってきましたが、いかがでしょうか？
We started from the beginning and went through spring, summer, and now autumn, what do you think?
こんなね、こういうね綺麗綺麗パワーとね、もうジラーチの力を借りて、きっとアイドルパワー溜まったんじゃないかな？どうだ？
With this beautiful power and borrowing Jirachi's strength, I'm sure my idol power has filled up, right? How is it?
アイドルパワーは？
How's the idol power?
お、来た。
Oh, it came.
おっ、上がってる！
Oh, it's going up!
おっ、やったねみんなの、ほら見て、めっちゃくちゃ上がってる！
Oh, yay! Look everyone, it's rising like crazy!
おっ、おっ、めっちゃ上がってるじゃん。すごい！
Oh, wow, it's going up a lot. Amazing!
みんなのこの注入のおかげ、ちょっとみんな注入して、注入して、
Thanks to everyone's infusion, everyone infuse, infuse...
え、ちょっと待って、今下がったんだけど。
Wait a second, it just went down.
え？嘘でしょ？ちょ、下がらないで！ちょ、みんなのがいっぱい注入してるから！
Eh? No way? Hey, don't drop! Hey, everyone is infusing so much!
ちょっとやめて、下がらないで！ちょっと、注入、注入、注入…
Stop it, don't drop! Hey, infuse, infuse, infuse...
あっ、ちょ、なんで下がるの！？なんで！？なんで！？
Ah, wait, why is it dropping?! Why?! Why?!
なんでなんでなんでなんでなんで…
Why, why, why, why, why...
あっ、そう、そうそうそう、注入、注入、注入、おっ、おっ、あっ、来た！
Ah, right, right right right, infuse, infuse, infuse... Oh, oh, ah, it's here!
あっ、やったー！上がったー！みんなの協力ありがとう！
Yay! It went up! Thank you everyone for your cooperation!
危ねえ！風真1人だったら下がるとこだったでござる！
That was close! If it were just Kazama, it would have dropped!
やった、え？なんか今速報が…
Yay! Eh? Wait, some breaking news...
あっ、なんかTwitterのハッシュタグがトレンド1位みたい！
Ah, looks like the Twitter hashtag is trending #1!
やった！みんなのおかげだ、めっちゃパワー注入してくれたおかげでござる！
Yay! Thanks to everyone for infusing so much power!
ありがとうございます！草の数々も撮ってくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you very much! Thanks for taking all those screenshots too!
このままね、あの、アイドルパワーマックスまで突っ走っていきたいと思いますので、みんな最後まで応援してください！
From here on, I want to dash all the way to maximum idol power, so everyone please cheer me on until the end!
って言っても、あとこのちょっとの壁が大きいんでござるよな。
Having said that, there's still a big final wall left.
まあ、我々ね、ホロックス1周年記念配信リレーということで風真がやっておりますが、
Well, as holoX's 1st anniversary stream relay finishes up with Kazama,
やっぱりアイドルになった我々の力ということ最後は、
representing the power of us who became idols,
あいつらを呼ぶか！
let's call those guys for the finale!
明日、今日よりも好きになれる 溢れる想いが止まらない
I'll love you more tomorrow than today, these overflowing emotions won't stop.
今もこんなに好きでいるのに 言葉にできない
Even though I love you this much right now, I can't put it into words.
君のくれた日々が積み重なり
The days you've given me accumulate,
過ぎ去った日々2人歩いた軌跡
the path we walked together through the past days.
過ぎ去った日々 2人歩いた軌跡
The days that have passed, the path we walked together.
僕らの出会いがもし偶然ならば? 運命ならば?
If our meeting was a coincidence? Or fate?
君に巡り合えた それって奇跡
Just being able to meet you is a miracle.
明日、今日よりも好きになれる
I'll love you more tomorrow than today
溢れる想いが止まらない
These overflowing emotions won't stop
今もこんなに好きでいるのに
Right now I love you so much
言葉に出来ない
I can't even put it into words
君のくれた日々が積み重なり
The days you've given me accumulate
過ぎ去った日々 2人歩いた「軌跡」
The days that have passed, the paths we walked together is a trail
いつも君の右の手の平を
Always, your right palm
ただ僕の左の手の平が
Just meeting my left palm
そっと包んでくれるそれだけで
Just gently wrapping around it
ただ愛を感じていた
I could feel your love
日々の中で 小さな幸せ 見つけ重ね
Finding and stacking small happinesses day by day
僕らの出会いは 大きな世界で
Our meeting in a big world
小さな出来事 巡り合えた
A small event where we met
それって「奇跡」
That is a "miracle"
うまくいかない日だって 2人でおれば晴れだって！
Even on bad days, being together makes it clear!
強がりや寂しさも 忘れられるから
Because I can forget my bravado and loneliness
僕は君で ならば僕で居れるから
I am with you, so I can be myself
だからいつも そばにいてよ 愛しい君へ
So always stay by my side, my beloved
想いよ届けと伝えた時に
When I told you to let my feelings reach you
初めて見せた表情の君
The expression you showed for the first time
少し間が空いて 君がうなづいて
After a slight pause, you nodded
僕らの心満たされてく愛で
With love filling our hearts
まだ旅の途中だから またこれから先も
We're still on our journey, so from here on too
たとえばほら 明日を見失いそうに 僕らなったとしても、
For instance, even if we seem to lose sight of tomorrow,
何十年 何百年 何千年 時を超えていこう
Let's go beyond time for tens, hundreds, thousands of years
2人寄り添って歩いて 永遠の愛を形にして
Walking close together, making our eternal love tangible
いつでも君の横で 笑っていたくて
Wanting to always smile by your side
アリガトウや Ah 愛してるじゃまだ足りないけど
\"Thank you\" and, ah, \"I love you\" just aren't enough
せめて言わせて 「幸せです」と
At least let me say \"I'm happy\"
うまくいかない日だって 2人でおれば晴れだって！
Even on bad days, being together makes it clear!
喜びや悲しみも 全て分け合える
We can share all our joys and sorrows
君がいるから 生きていけるから
Because you are here, I can live on
だからいつも そばにいてよ 愛しい君へ
So always stay by my side, my beloved
明日、今日よりも笑顔になれる
I'll smile more tomorrow than today
君がいるだけで そう思えるから
Just having you here makes me feel that way
何十年 何百年 何千年 時を超えていこう
Let's go beyond time for tens, hundreds, thousands of years
君を愛している
I love you
ホロックスの5人でございます！
We are the five members of HoloX!
イェーイ！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
というわけで、ホロックスで「キセキ」を歌わせていただきました！みんな今日は来てくれてありがとうございます！
And that's why we performed \"Kiseki\" as HoloX! Thank you everyone for coming today!
イェーイ！おめでとう！ありがとう！
Yay! Congratulations! Thank you!
実はデビューしてからずっと夢だったことがあって、ホロックスのチャンネルにホロックスが揃ったことなかったから
Actually, it's been my dream since debut, because all of HoloX had never gathered on the HoloX channel before...
確かに！そうか！1周年までにみんなに来てほしいなって思ってたら、あっという間に1年経ちました！
That's right! True! I was hoping everyone would come by our 1st anniversary, and before we knew it, a whole year has passed!
よかったね！とつましとか来てくれたことはあったけど、自分からみんなを呼べて本当に嬉しいでございます！ありがとう！
I'm so glad! People have dropped by before, but being able to invite everyone myself makes me truly happy! Thank you!
呼んでくれてありがとう！こちらこそありがとう！
Thank you for inviting us! Thank you too!
よし、みんなのおかげでアイドルゲージがたくさん増えたのでわー！
Alright, thanks to everyone, our idol gauge increased so much, wow!
上がってる！やばい！上がってる！みんなのおかげで全部溜まったでございます！ありがとう！
It's going up! No way! It's going up! Thanks to everyone, it's completely filled up! Thank you!
よし、これでパソコンが直りそうなのでラストスパートも頑張るでございます！ノヴァ！
Alright, since this looks like it'll fix the PC, we'll do our best for the final spurt too! Nova!
それじゃあみんなまたアジトで会おうね！
Well then, let's meet again at the hideout, everyone!
はじまったね
It's started!
はじまったー
It started!
がんばってね 頑張ってねー！
Do your best! Good luck!
げんまのぽこべえさーん！
Master Pokobee!
先ほどアイドルパワーがマックスになったでござるが、
The idol power reached max earlier,
まだ直ってないでござるな、煙も出てるし、火花もバチバチだー！
but it still hasn't fixed itself, it's smoking, and sparking everywhere!
おかしいな、さっきパワーマックスになったはずなのに。
That's strange, it should've maxed out earlier...
ああごめんぽこべ、おつこまないで、ごめんで、お？
Ah sorry Pokobee, don't get depressed, sorry, oh?
どうした？どうした？
What's wrong? What's wrong?
おもむろになにをお取り出すんだ、待ってるぞ風間は。
What are you slowly pulling out? Kazama is waiting.
大丈夫か？怪我、怪我しないでほしいでござるよ。
Are you okay? I hope you don't get hurt.
お？
Oh?
ちょっと待て！まさかお前、それはまずい！
Wait a minute! No way, man, that's bad!
それはまずい！たった一日直らないことは一連で学んだって！
That's bad! You learned in one series that waiting a day doesn't fix it!
やめとけ！
Stop it!
ああ危ない！壊れる！壊れる！壊れる！やめろ！あ、そこっ！
Ah dangerous! It'll break! Stop it! Ah, right there!
ツイッター！壊れたぞ！
Twitter! It broke!
ツイッターんだ けど、え？ぽこべえすごい！
Twittered, but, eh? Pokobee is amazing!
ぽこべえすごいよ！ありがとうぽこべえ！
Pokobee, you're amazing! Thank you, Pokobee!
ツイッター！やった！直ったー！
Twitter! Yay! It's fixed!
というわけで皆殿、パソコンさんが無事ばっちり直りましたー！
And so everyone, the PC has successfully and completely been fixed!
これでやっと一周年のために準備したあれやこれやこれや重大なデータが復活しました！
With this, all the important data prepared for the 1st anniversary has finally been restored!
よし！ここからがね、ラストスパート！皆殿、ちゃんと最後まで見ていてくださいねー！
Alright! From here is the final spurt! Everyone, please be sure to watch all the way to the end!
誰かに与えられた色をままとって
Wearing the colors given to me by someone,
違う誰かを演じてきた
I've played different roles.
胸に手を当てて歌う
Putting my hand to my chest as I sing,
「これが私だ」って言い聞かせるように
as if to remind myself, "This is me."
憧れにはほど遠く 落ち込むばかりの毎日で
Far from what I long for, with days filled only with getting down,
閉ざされた瞳から 雫がこぼれ落ちてゆく
from closed eyes, teardrops start to spill and fall.
何千回 私が生まれ変わったとしても
Even if I were to be reborn a thousand times,
きっともう二度と 私にはなれやしないから
I'm sure I could never become myself again, so
本当の私を偽りのないこの色を
putting my true self, these unfaked colors,
歌声にのせて モノクロの世界を彩るよ
into my song, I'll color the monochrome world.
誰かにのぞまれた色を探し 見つけるために歩いてきた
Searching for the colors someone wanted me to have, I've walked to find them,
あるいてきた
and walked onward.
気づけば現在地もゴールも 見失って迷子になっていた
Only to realize I'd lost sight of both my current place and goal, becoming a lost child.
無理やり笑顔を作って 自分をだますことばかり
Forcing a smile, always just deceiving myself,
青く澄んだ空から 雫がこぼれ落ちてきた
from the clear blue sky, raindrops came spilling down.
何千回 私が光を浴びたとしても
Even if I were bathed in light a thousand times,
嘘を重ねた色じゃ輝けないから
colors piled with lies can't shine, so
本当の私を偽りのないこの色を
holding my true self, these unfaked colors close,
強く抱きしめて 雨あがりのかすみを探しに行くよ
I'll go search for the rainbow after the rain.
坂道にゆくよ
Walking up the slope.
不器用で
Clumsy,
つよがりで
stubborn,
泣き虫で
a crybaby,
頼りなくて
and unreliable...
でも
But
それもこれも全部
I'll accept all of that
受け止めていくんだ
and keep moving forward.
何千回 私が 生まれ変わったとしても
Even if I were reborn a thousand times,
きっと もう二度と 私にはなれやしないから
I could never become this "me" again.
本当の 私を 偽りのないこの色を
My true self, this unfeigned color—
歌声にのせて モノクロの世界を 彩るよ
I'll put it in my voice and paint the monochrome world.
何千回 私が 冷たい雨が降っても
A thousand times, even when cold rain falls,
歌声にのせて モノクロの世界も
putting it into my song, the monochrome world
鮮やかに彩るよ
I will vividly color it...
私の色で
with my own colors.
はい！というわけで
Yes! So,
覚えていますか、皆のの、40mPさんの「Color of Drops」
do you all remember 40mP-san's "Color of Drops"?
デビュー配信の時にパソコン壊しちゃって、お披露目できなかった曲を、1周年でダンス付きでお届けさせていただきました！やったー！
During my debut stream, my PC broke and I couldn't debut this song, but I finally delivered it with a dance for my 1st anniversary! Yay!
届いた！みんなのパソコン直ったよ！
It went through! Everyone, my PC is fixed!
画面は壊れちゃったけどみんなの温かい応援のおかげで直りました！ありがとうございます！
The screen broke, but thanks to everyone's warm support, it's fixed! Thank you so much!
そして、じゃーん！見てください！
And now, ta-da! Please take a look!
風真のアイドル衣装このようになっております！
Kazama's idol outfit looks like this!
しょ、ぽんっ（笑）どうですか？
Ta-da! How is it?
想像してたのと皆のと合ってた？どう？どうどうどうどう？
Was it what you all imagined? How is it? How do you like it?
後ろもね、結構あの風真のイメージカラーをいっぱいね入れていただいて、
On the back, too, we've incorporated plenty of Kazama's image colors,
足元とかもこの、あ、こっちか、通常衣装のね、靴したの、ついに、なっております！
and for the feet—ah, this side—it's finally matched with the normal outfit's socks!
え、どうでござるか？可愛い、本当に、可愛いしかない。
What do you think? It's so cute, truly, nothing but cute.
そう、このタイプかってコメントあったら、そう、風真はこのタイプになりました！
Yes, if you were wondering if it's this type, Kazama became this type!
そして気づきました？カラーオブドロップ始まる前に、
And did you notice? Before "Color of Drops" started,
なんかパソコンが直ったから、ここ！じゃん！
since my PC got fixed, right here! Ta-da!
オリジナルのマイクを手に入れましたー！やったー！
I got my original microphone! Yay!
本当にね、これもね、あのすごい1周年配信まで準備していたものなんですけど、
Truly, this is something we prepared right up until the 1st-anniversary stream,
あのパソコン故障して一時はどうなるかと思いました。でも無事にね、みんなのおかげで直りました！ありがとうございます！
but when the PC broke, I wondered what would happen. But thanks to everyone, it was safely fixed! Thank you!
そして、もう一つ、もう気づきかもしれませんか、
And one more thing, you might have already noticed,
ステージ冬になりました！
the stage has become winter!
ざむ、風真は、寒いところから来た侍だからまだ耐えられるけど、これは風真じゃなかったら耐えられなかったでござるな。寒い。
Kazama is a samurai from a cold place so I can still endure it, but if it weren't Kazama, I wouldn't have been able to bear it. It's cold.
寒いけど、ほら！雪景色きれいでしょう！冬になりました！
It's cold, but look! The snow scenery is so pretty! It became winter!
秋からスタートして、冬までここまでやってきました！風真のね、デビューの奇跡をね、同じようになぞらせていただきましたが、
Starting from autumn, we've made it all the way to winter! We traced the miracle of Kazama's debut in the same way,
やっぱり風真も1周年、もちろん出ます！
but of course, Kazama's 1st anniversary has something else too!
あれが、そう！グッズです！お待たせしました！
That is, yes! Goods! Thank you for waiting!
それでは詳細は、こちら！
Now, here are the details!
はい、風真いろは活動1周年記念のグッズ、11月30日販売開始でございます！
Yes, Kazama Iroha's 1st-anniversary commemoration goods go on sale November 30th!
見て！めちゃくちゃ可愛い！
Look! They're super cute!
もう、もうね、いろいろ天才すぎてね、ちょっと尺足りるかなって思うんでござるが、ちょっと説明させていただきますね。
They're just too genius, I think we might run out of time, but let me explain them one by one.
じゃあまずはラバーマットから！はい、こちらでござる！
First is the rubber mat! Yes, right here!
今回はね、また描いてもらいました！うみぼうずママ様に描いていただきました！
This time, too, we had it drawn! Umibouzu-mama-sama drew it for us!
このステージでね、いっぱい踊ってる風真をね、撮ってもらいました！ママちゃんありがとう！ありがとうございまーす！
She captured Kazama dancing so much on this stage! Thank you, Mama-chan! Thank you so much!
ね、是非いっぱい使ってほしいです！そして2つ目！
I really want you all to use it a lot! And second!
はい、3連結アクリルキーホルダー！
Yes, the 3-connected acrylic keychain!
こちらのイラストは、風真のメンバーシップスタンプなどをね、ご担当いただいております、すずみしろ先生にご担当いただきました！ありがとうございます！
This illustration was handled by Suzumishiro-sensei, who also does Kazama's membership stamps! Thank you!
なかったようで、あ、あったようでなかった、チャキ丸のキーホルダーがね、追加されておりまして、風真とぽこべぇとチャキ丸、3つね、つながるキーホルダーになって…
It seems we've added a Chakimaru keychain, which we hadn't had before—well, actually we didn't have it, so now Kazama, Pokobee, and Chakimaru are connected in a 3-piece keychain...
いますので、ぶら下げて連れてってね。
So please hang it and take it with you!
そして次！これも頑張りました。
And next! I worked hard on this too.
こちら、今回風真がデザインさせていただきました、ポコべのスマホリングでござる！
This is Pokobee's smartphone ring,
which Kazama designed this time!
かわいいでしょ！
Isn't it cute?!
ちょっと頑張ってデザインしてみました。
I really tried hard to design it.
なんかデビューの最初からね、ポコべのお尻は何かつれで作りたいなと思っていたので、
Ever since my debut, I've wanted to make
some kind of Pokobee butt merchandise,
今回はスマホリングにしてみました。みなさんのね、毎日使ってるスマホにぜひっつけて、
so this time I made it into a smartphone ring.
Please attach it to your everyday smartphone,
ポコべと一緒に連れてってくれると嬉しいなって思います。
and take Pokobee along with you!
そして、もうこれ超大物、みんな待ってたでしょ！これです！
And now, the long-awaited item
everyone's been waiting for! This is it!
ポコべのぬいぐるみです！
Pokobee's plushie!
やっとみなぞるのおうちにもポコべがお迎えできるようになりました！
Minazor's homes can finally
welcome Pokobee!
みんながポコべ欲しい、ポコべ欲しいよ、うちにも来てくれって言っててくれたので、
Everyone kept saying "I want Pokobee,
come to my house too,"
ポコべね、ここ数日ルーズにしていたんですが、出張してぬいぐるみのサンプルになってまいりました。
so Pokobee's been loose these past few days,
but he went on a business trip
どうだ、かわいいだろポコべ！
How's that, isn't Pokobee cute?!
え、かわいい？
Huh, cute?
金色ポコべっていうの、おい、金色ポコべっていうのやめろ！
Golden Pokobee? Hey, stop calling him
golden Pokobee!
で も、でも、でも、でも、かわいいでしょ？かわいいでしょ？
But, but, but, isn't he cute?
Isn't he cute?
風真もね、ちょっと大量に購入して、あの枕の周りにいっぱいつこうと思います。
Kazama bought a bunch of them too,
and I'm going to put tons around my pillow.
よろしくお願いします。スタッフさんにも大人気です。ありがとうございます。
Please look forward to it. It's super popular
with the staff too. Thank you!
そしてそしてフルセットがね、このようになっております。どどん！
And now, the full set is like this.
Ta-da!
ね、ありがとうございます。そしてフルセットをご購入していただきますと、
Thank you so much. Also, if you purchase
the full set,
風真いろは箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入り、うみぼうず先生の描き下ろしポストカードがついてくるのと、
you'll get a postcard illustrated by Umibozu-sensei
with Kazama's foil-stamped signature and message!
特典ボイスです！特典ボイス頑張って撮ったよ！
plus a bonus voice! I worked hard
recording the bonus voice!
ライブ終わりのね、控室でのね、あのシチュエーションボイスとなっております。
It's a situation voice in the dressing room
right after the live.
頑張って撮ってきたりましたので、あの、恥ずかしいんですけど、ちょっと緊張している風真、
I worked hard recording it, so it's a bit
embarrassing, but Kazama is a bit nervous,
そして、あの、ライブが終わって頑張ったなあってなっている風真とのね、ひと時を一緒に過ごしてもらえたら、嬉しいなと思います。
and if you could spend a little time together
with Kazama after the live, I'd be so happy!
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
はい、この後21時から販売開始であってるかな？
Yep, sales start at 21:00, right?
と思いますので、ぜひぜひチェックしてくださいお願いします。
I think so, so please be sure
to check it out!
デザインとか色々頑張ったから、みなぞるの手に届くと嬉しいです。
I worked hard on the designs, so I'd be happy
if they reach Minazoru's hands.
そして、メンバーシップのね、この後配信があります。
Also, there's a membership stream
right after this.
21時15分からメンゲン配信がありますので、アフタ、アフタ、アフタートーク、あ、そしてね、ライブ周り、写真撮影周り、
Starting at 21:15, there will be a member stream,
so after-talk, live wrap-up, and photos...
なんでも周り、そしてまだまだここで出していないあんなやこうなのひろめがたくさんありますので、メンバーシップの方はぜひ遊びに来てください。
and there are still so many unreleased tidbits,
so members, please come hang out!
そして21時からはメンバーシップ限定の壁紙も、あの公開されます。
And starting at 21:00, membership-limited
wallpapers will also be released.
今回ね、サムネご担当いただきました、春丸先生にね、メンバーシップ限定用のサブも書いていただいておりますので、あの、絶対にね、お見逃しなくチェックしてください。
Harumaru-sensei has drawn a sub illustration
exclusively for members, so don't miss it!
はい。いっぱい、いっぱい喋ったな。いっぱい喋ったね。
Yeah. I talked so much.
I really talked a lot.
ここまでね、1年いろいろありました。
A lot has happened over this past year.
正直ね、パソコン壊しちゃって今日どうしようってなってたんでござるが、別にまず配信できてよかったです。
Honestly, my PC broke and I was wondering
what to do today, but I'm glad I could stream.
今日風真からね、みなぞるにね、いっぱいありがとうは
Today Kazama has a lot of thank-yous
to give to Minazoru,
あるんですが、他にもありがとうね、いっぱい伝えたい人がいます。
but there are also many others
I want to thank.
まず、このライブのね、先輩方がここまでね、あの支えてくださり、
First of all, to all the seniors who supported
this live up to now,
本当にありがとうございました。
thank you so much.
そしてね、運営スタッフさんもここまでね、本当ライブの準備とか大変だからね、
And to the management staff, live preparation
is really tough,
あの一生懸命動いてくださって本当にありがとうございましたでござる。
so thank you so much for working
your hardest for us.
そして、ホロックスのみんな見てるか？見てるでござるか？見てる？ホロックス。
And Holorx members, are you watching?
Are you watching? Are you watching, Holorx?
ちょっとね、5人で色々悩んだり励まし合ったり、ここまでしてこれて、そして1年をね、5人で迎えられて
The five of us worried and encouraged each other,
making it this far, and welcoming our 1st year together
本当に本当に嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
makes me truly, truly happy. Thank you.
頼りない用心棒ですが、ここからもまあ、
I'm an unreliable bodyguard, but from here on out too
ジャキンジャキンしていくのでよろしくお願いします。
I'll keep pushing forward sharp and strong,
so please look after me.
ありがとう、ホロックスのみんな大好きでござる。
Thank you, I love everyone in Holorx.
そして、大将のみなぞるも今日も配信見てくれてありがとうございます。
And to my boss Minazoru, thank you
for watching the stream today too.
ちょっとね、いらたにないことばっかりの体調ですが、この2年目も強くなったところね、
My physical condition has been a bit unstable,
but in this 2nd year...
いっぱいいろいろ見せていきたいと思いますので、
I want to show you how much stronger
I've become,
目をそらさず、そらさず、そらさないで、目を離さず、しっかりとついてきてください。
so please keep your eyes on me without looking away,
and stick close by me.
風真もこの2年目はもっともっともっと頑張ります。
Kazama will work even harder, harder, harder
in this 2nd year.
よろしくお願いします！
Please treat me well!
よし！言いたいこと全部言った！全部言ったね！
Alright! I said everything I wanted to say!
I said it all!
みなぞるありがとう！これからもよろしくお願いします。
Thank you, Minazoru!
Please keep supporting me from now on.
それでは、ずっと待っていただろうこの発表をさせていただきます。お待ちお待たせしました！
Now then, I will make the announcement
you've all been waiting for.
待望の風真いろはオリジナルソングが、発売決定しました！やったーー！
Thanks for waiting! Kazama Iroha's
original song release has been decided!
この後24時からは販売開始
And sales start at 24:00!
でございますので、ぜひぜひチェックしてください。
As this is available, please be sure to check it out!
曲名は「いろはすてっぷ！」！
The song title is "Iroha Step!"!
はい、曲は40mPさんに作っていただきまして、
Yes, the song was composed by 40mP,
ええと、こちらのね、ジャケットイラストはツムミ先生、
and the jacket illustration was handled by Tsumumi-sensei,
ロゴは柊りお先生にご担当いただきました！
and the logo by Hiiragi Rio-sensei!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
たくさんたくさん元気が出る曲なんでね、
It's a song that gives you so much energy,
たくさんたくさん皆さんどおりに聴いてもらえると嬉しいです。
so I'd be so happy if everyone listens to it a lot.
よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it!
やばいちょっと待って、泣く前にね、もうもう泣く前に、
Oh no, wait, before I cry, already before I cry,
この熱がね、冷めないうちに
while this excitement hasn't cooled down yet,
この、今発表したオリジナル曲を歌って踊ります！
I'm going to sing and dance to the original song I just announced!
それでは聴いてください、風真いろはオリジナルソング「いろはすてっぷ！」
So please listen to Kazama Iroha's original song, "Iroha Step!"!
風がそっと吹いたら
When the wind softly blows,
始まる合図でござる！
it's the signal to begin!
Ah このハードモードな日々
Ah, through these hard-mode days,
Days 歩き出すことためらうけど
days when I hesitate to take a step,
BGM決めて さあ、人生エンジョイ勢で
choose your BGM, come on, with an enjoyment mindset,
のんびりゆこう
let's take it easy.
先の見えない乱世
In this turbulent age with no sight of the future,
自分の道とやりんせ
walk your own path as you please.
オーケー 生きてりゃきっと
Okay, if you stay alive, surely
なんとかなるさ
things will somehow work out.
大丈夫 大丈夫！
It's gonna be alright, it's gonna be alright!
後ろ前 方向なんてわからない
Backward, forward, I don't know which way is which,
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
even in these labyrinth-like days,
一歩 歩き出せたら
if you can take just one step forward,
それが前になるのさ
that becomes 'forward'.
万事快調気分な朝でも
Even on a morning when everything feels great,
頭滞気味な夜でも
or a night when your head feels sluggish,
風がいつも吹いてる
the wind is always blowing.
心配しないで
Don't worry,
一緒にファイトでござる！
let's do our best together!
Ah まだ履き慣れていない
Ah, these shoes I'm still not used to wearing
シューズ 転びそうになってばかり
have me constantly on the verge of tripping.
七転び八起き 何回でもゲームオーバー
Fall seven times, rise eight, game over however many times,
コンティニューしよう
let's just continue!
地獄の沙汰も自分次第 たまにミスって非常事態
Even the judgment of hell depends on yourself; sometimes a mistake leads to an emergency,
シーザス 生きてりゃそういう時だってあるさ
jeez, living means having times like that too.
大丈夫 大丈夫！
It's gonna be alright, it's gonna be alright!
右左 1･2･3が聞こえない
Right and left, 1, 2, 3 can't be heard,
もはや突発的な運命も
even sudden, unexpected destinies,
グッド タイミングな予感
feel like good timing.
思い立ったが吉日さ
The day you decide to do something is the auspicious day.
いつも現実主義なあの人も
Even that person who's always a realist,
かたや妄想癖な誰かも
or someone prone to delusions,
夢の中で会えたら
if we can meet in a dream,
遊び明かしましょう
let's play the night away.
それじゃあね おやすみ
Well then, good night.
色は匂へと散りぬるを
Though flowers bloom only to scatter,
終わりのないはじまりを
let's sing of an endless beginning
歌いながら風のままに
while drifting with the wind.
ゆけ！
Go!
後ろ前 方向なんてわからない
Backward, forward, I don't know which way is which,
こんな迷宮入りな毎日も
even in these labyrinth-like days,
一歩 歩き出せたら
if you can take just one step forward,
それが前になるのさ
that becomes 'forward'.
万事快調気分な朝でも
Even on a morning when everything feels great,
頭滞気味な夜でも
or a night when your head feels sluggish,
風がいつも吹いてる
the wind is always blowing.
心配しないで
Don't worry,
自分のペースで 一緒にファイトでござる！
at your own pace, let's do our best together!
ござる！
Gorru!